Let's go.
We'll be right back.
Faded mother and daughter.
The mother's name is Ovia.
It's been a while, hasn't it?
It's Ovia.
You came back.
We heard news that you've been captured by the Navy.
Don't tell me you came back on their ship.
I hate to have to tell you this as soon as I return, but the news you heard is true.
It's not your fault.
We knew the government would set its sights on Ohara eventually.
I'm not sure how much you know, but the Poneglyph search team that set off six years ago was annihilated by the Marines.
Thirty-three researchers were killed.
I was the... the only survivor.
Fortunately, I was only captured.
But I overheard the Marines talking after they had rummaged through the search team's belongings.
They soon realized that we all came from Ohara.
I won't make any excuses.
All of you are in danger because of my carelessness.
Stop it.
Thinking like that won't do any good.
Those who set out to sea and those who stayed behind are all part of the same team.
After what happened, if anyone should apologize, it's us.
We know how much you've suffered.
Professor.
For years now, the world government has seen Ohara as a threat to their rule.
But all we can do is believe in the truth of history and its value to all generations to come.
Be that as it may, they've put us in quite a compromising position.
I just don't know how we're going to get out of this one.
I admit, it doesn't look good.
But we're fortunate to have discovered this information when we did.
We know that the government is hunting down all the scholars on the island.
So before they make it to the library, we have to escape from Ohara.
You have a point.
This time I have a feeling we won't be able to slip past their investigation like we have before.
And if they're committed to killing us, they won't listen to reason either.
Then hurry up and run!
I'm sorry, Olvia.
I can't let myself escape and leave one of mankind's greatest treasures behind.
You should know that.
Everyone else here feels the same way.
Yeah.
Are you sure?
We still don't know what the government's going to do when they get here.
But we do know if we run, we can't protect all this precious knowledge.
We're not planning on dying here.
Don't worry.
More importantly, I know you have something else weighing on your mind.
I can't.
It's too late for that.
Make up your mind, Olvia.
Are you going to board this ship or not?
If you want to stay with your daughter, we'll settle your husband's unfinished business for you.
No, I'm not turning back.
I'm a scholar of Ohara.
It's my duty to carry out the will of those who came before me.
Forgive me, Robin.
I swear, I'll solve these mysteries and come back to you someday.
Where's my mommy?
Where'd she go?
Your mom had to go out to sea for her job.
You'll be staying here with us for a little while, okay?
That's enough.
If you don't shut up, I'll hit you.
Honey, stop it.
She's only two.
And so is our daughter.
Listen, I don't care if she's your sister's child.
She's a burden.
This was a mistake.
Who's there?
What are you doing here?
Uh, I was, I, I mean, I just, uh.
I'm so sorry.
If you want to read a book, all you have to do is ask, all right?
But I can't because I don't have any money.
Well, then looks like you're in luck because you can read everything here for free.
For free?
Uh-huh.
After all, this library is the best in the world.
It is? Really?
Sure is.
Let's see.
Unless I'm mistaken, you're Olvia's daughter.
You like to read books?
Mm-hmm.
She looks just like you did when you were that age.
And I'm proud to say she's every bit as clever, too.
If she's safe, that's enough.
When I decided to join you, I severed all bonds with her.
I can't let her become the daughter of a criminal.
Bad news!
Another ship came with the world government's flag!
One of their high-ranked officials coming all the way here to the West Blue?
My goodness.
It seems this is quite serious indeed.
All right, everyone, listen.
From now on, you and I are neither colleagues nor acquaintances.
You have to stick to that no matter what.
Farewell!
Olvia, wait!
What are you going to do?
All right.
Tell HQ we've arrived.
Let's move it.
I want to get this over with.
What a pain.
They better give me a promotion when this crap is over.
Hey!
I want you to hunt down every scholar on the island and restrain them.
Yes, sir!
What's going on?
Some woman is running around with a gun!
This is an awful mess.
I'm sorry, Robin.
Vice Admiral Kuzan.
What is it?
We've been informed that CP-9's Chief Spondyne has arrived at Ohara.
So what?
Did you really have to wake me up?
Just to tell me that?
I'm sorry, sir!
What's the matter, Robin?
You have to tell me, didn't my mom come by here?
Now hold on a minute.
Where did that come from?
Why would you think your mother was back in Ohara?
I've severed all bonds.
No matter what, I can't let her become the daughter of a criminal.
I wish she was here too, but she's not.
Oh yeah!
We're in trouble!
I heard there are navy battleships coming to the island right now!
They're trying to get rid of all the scholars on Ohara!
The people in town must be stirring up bad rumors.
The truth is, that's no battleship, and they won't be getting rid of anyone.
The government is paying us a visit, though.
And that means the library will be under an investigation.
A harsh one.
So listen up.
No matter what those government agents say or do,
you absolutely cannot let them know that you're an archaeologist like the rest of us.
Since you're so young, as long as you keep quiet, no one will think you're a scholar.
You understand?
Move it!
Stop what you're doing!
Put your hands in the air and go outside!
Don't you think you're being a bit violent?
The researchers here at the Tree of Knowledge are being charged with the heinous crime of deciphering poneglyphs.
We'll be investigating the library, so everyone get out of our way and leave the building.
You'd better treat this place with care.
The value of this collection is well beyond your imagination, I assure you.
I don't have to listen to a word you say.
Take him outside!
Yes, sir!
Attention, citizens of Ohara!
I regret to inform you that the scholars of this island may be devils in disguise plotting to destroy the world.
What? But why?
Our scholars are the pride of every person in Ohara!
They would never dream of doing something like that!
From this point forward, we will be conducting a large-scale search of the entire island.
During that time, all those who are not related to the research center must take a form of identification
and head to the evacuation ship on the west seashore.
Evacuation? That's ridiculous!
Even if the scholars did do something wrong that still has nothing to do with us,
you can't kick us off our own island!
Our only obligation was to pass on this message to you.
Disregard our warning if you like, but we won't be held responsible should any unfortunate accidents occur.
You heard him?
Yeah, everyone! Back to the west shore!
I don't want to have any part of this mess!
I've been shot! This is it for me!
I'm a gunner, damn it! A gunner!
Contact the higher-ups!
Tell them I want my son to take over for me!
Calm down, Chief. Just take a look.
The bullet went through your sleeve, that's all.
Oh, I see.
I'll aim to kill next time.
Well, if it isn't Nico Olvia.
I find it hard to believe that a devious criminal like you would end up on this island completely by coincidence after your daring escape.
In other words, despite the fact that you've denied your connection to the scholars of Ohara,
you've shown up at their doorstep just in time to warn them of our little investigation.
Now, in my humble opinion, that very clearly labels them as your partners in crime.
You've no idea why I'm here. That doesn't prove one single thing.
Hmm. I'm sure you've cooked up plenty of excuses to cover for them.
You're a clever woman, after all.
But that doesn't really matter, because we don't have to prove your connection to the Ohara scholars anymore.
Now that we're here, we can search every little nook and cranny.
I doubt it'll take long before we find evidence of their poneglyph research.
The government's quite confident in this, and you know they're never wrong.
This has been in the works for a long time.
Capturing you after six years of hide-and-seek was nothing more than the final push.
There are plenty of poneglyph researchers around the world,
and each time we captured one, we tried to find any connection they might have to Ohara.
Can you guess why that is?
Don't tell me. You're making an example of us?
Exactly. If we crush this holy ground of archaeology, the entire academic world will take notice.
It's the perfect opportunity to show the world exactly what happens to those who research the blank century.
Then, the battleships from headquarters waiting on standby are here, too.
Well, look at that. You are a clever woman, aren't you?
Yes, as you might guess, there to ensure that not even a single criminal escapes.
However, as a matter of form, we still need to verify their guilt.
We aren't pirates, after all.
So I came all this way to conduct a compulsory investigation of the island
and chase off anyone who's not involved.
It's curtains for you and your friends.
There's no escape.
Take her down.
Hey, what are you doing? All the books here are world treasures.
Take them outside and shut them up.
Move it!
You bastards!
They must have a secret room somewhere around here.
Don't stop until you find it!
This is worse than I thought!
The battleships are here already and there's a whole mess of them!
That should be everyone!
Good! Now don't let them go anywhere!
Look, they're rounding up all the scholars!
What did they do wrong?
We'll be right back.
What about you, Mom? Aren't you coming with me?
I'm afraid there's still something that I have to do here.
No, I don't want to lose you.
I want to stay together from now on.
Please.
On the next, One Piece, the tragedy of Ohara,
the terror of the Buster Call,
I'm going to be king of the pirates.